cellsignal.com 2017-07-11

# Privacy Policy | Cell Signaling Technology

### CST AND ITS APPROACH TO PRIVACY

Founded by research scientists in 1999, Cell Signaling Technology, Inc. (CST) is a private, family-owned company headquartered in Danvers, Massachusetts, U.S. CST employs over 400 people worldwide, including at subsidiaries in the Netherlands (CST Europe, B.V.) (also known as Bioke, B.V.), Japan (Cell Signaling Technology Japan, K.K.), and CST (Shanghai) Biologic Reagents Trading Co., LTD.) (collectively referred to as “CST”). CST sells its products directly and through distributors in twenty-six countries. The same CST scientists who produce our products also provide direct technical support and education via telephone, webcasts or in-person at conferences and vendor shows offered at many locations around the globe.

This privacy policy describes how CST collects, stores, processes, transfers, shares and uses data that identifies or is associated with you (hereinafter "Personal Information") whether this information is collected directly from you during a direct interaction with us, such as at a conference or by telephone, and, any indirect collection of information, such as your interactions with this website (“Site”) or any applications we may offer (“Apps”) (collectively, “Internet Services”). This privacy policy applies to all CST Internet Services, including:

  1. [WWW.CELLSIGNAL.COM](https://www.cellsignal.com/)
  2. [WWW.CSTJ.CO.JP](http://www.cstj.co.jp/)
  3. [WWW.CST-C.COM.CN](http://www.cst-c.com.cn/)
  4. [WWW.BIOKE.COM](http://www.bioke.com/)
  5. [WWW.PHOSPHOSITE.ORG](http://www.phosphosite.org/)

CST operates these Internet Services utilizing certain third-party cloud-based applications for storage and processing of Personal Information. CST technical support, educational, and marketing functions occur in all of our regions, including in the U.S.

**International Transfers of your Personal Information: the Personal Information CST collects may be transferred to and stored in countries (including the US) outside of the jurisdiction you are in. Some of these jurisdictions offer differing levels of protection in respect of Personal Information and may, in certain instances, be less protective than the jurisdiction you are typically resident in. We take reasonable steps to ensure that your Personal Information is treated securely and in accordance with applicable law and this privacy policy.**

CST Internet Services use cookies to store and access information when you access our Internet Services. You can find out more about our use of cookies in our cookie policy.

Your continued use of the Internet Services or direct submission of Personal Information to CST (or to one of its distributors) constitutes your acceptance of CST’s collection and processing of your Personal Information in accordance with this policy.

### PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT ABOUT YOU AND HOW WE USE IT

We collect Personal Information about you when you voluntarily submit information directly to us. This can include information you provide to us when you complete a form, purchase products, correspond with us, subscribe to our mailing lists, newsletters or other forms of marketing communications, respond to a survey, enter a promotion or use some other feature of our Internet Service or when contacting us by telephone, interacting with us at a conference, vendor show, or when supplying information to a distributor.

We also collect Personal Information from you indirectly such as information about the pages you look at (via providers like Google analytics) or the device you use to access the Internet Services.

We also combine the Personal Information you give us with information we obtain from third parties, such as Google analytics, distributors, conference organizers, or webinar partners, as examples.  
The list below sets out the categories of Personal Information we collect about you and how we use that information.    
**Contact details:** We collect contact information such as your name, your email address, your organization, your telephone number and addresses associated with your account or order. We will use your contact details so that we can communicate with you directly about the products we sell, the services we provide, deliver products to you and about queries, issues or concerns you or other users have.   
**Your role** : We collect information about the organization you work for and your role within it.  We also collect information about your technical support needs, and projects or experiments you are working on.  We use this so we can better understand your needs and to better respond to your requests for information, products or services or technical support.  We will also use this information to determine products and services that may be of interest to you and to send you marketing communications in accordance with your marketing preferences.  
**Comments and opinions:** When you contact us directly, e.g. by email, phone, mail or by completing an online form we will record your comments and opinions.  We will also record comments and opinions you express when responding to surveys, entering competitions or taking part in promotions we run. We will use your comments and opinions to address your queries, issues and concerns, to offer technical support and to improve our products and services.  We will also use comments and opinions you express to determine products and services that may be of interest to you and to send you marketing communications in accordance with your marketing preferences.   
**Payment and transaction information:** We keep records of the products and services you purchase from us. We will use transaction information to process payment for any product or service you purchase from us. We will also use your transaction information and history to determine products and services that may be of interest to you and send you marketing communications in accordance with your marketing preferences.  CST is transitioning to a third-party payment provider who will be solely responsible for your payment transaction information. In the meantime, CST maintains payment information for one day, during the evening payment information is erased.   
**Website and app login details:** Where you create an account with us we will hold your user name and password details so that we can keep your account secure.   
**Your preferences** : We hold information about the preferences you set for notifications, marketing communications and how our site is displayed or what content is displayed to you through our app. We will use your preference settings for the purpose of providing notifications, sending marketing communications and displaying our site in accordance with your choices.  
**Information about how you use and connect to our site or our app:** We collect information about how you use our Internet Service such as the pages you view, the time of your access, and how long you use the Internet Services, navigational information such as which websites you visited before and after visiting ours, and any selections and choices you make during your visit.   
We also collect information about the computer, tablet, smartphone or other electronic device you use to connect to our Internet Service. This information can include details about the type of device, unique device identifying numbers, operating systems, browsers and applications connected to our site or our app through the device, your Internet service provider or mobile network, your IP address and your device's telephone number (if it has one).  
Typically, the information we collect about how you use or connect to our site is associated with your device and not you as a named individual. However, if you are logged into a registered account you have with us, this information may also be associated with you directly.  
We use Personal Information gathered in these ways to determine products, services, and educational opportunities that may be of interest to you and to call these to your attention from time to time.   
**Information about your location:** Other than information you choose to provide to us, we do not collect information about your precise location. Your device's IP address may help us determine an approximate location. We may use an approximate location to ensure content on our site is relevant to the area, city, state or country you are using your device in.   
**Information provided by other users:** Sometimes, other people, such as your work colleagues or distributors, provide information associated with you. We will use Personal Information about you that is contained in private messages sent to us by other users to fulfill and deliver orders and to respond to any query, issue or concern they raise.  Where users of our site or our app want to invite you to use our site, our app or to share information with you about our products and services we will use Personal Information that they provide about you to assist them in doing this; we will only do this though where they indicate that you have provided your consent for them to communicate with you in this way.  
**Information about fraudulent or criminal activity relating to your account:** We will use information about fraudulent or criminal activity relating to your use of our Internet Service for the purposes of detecting and preventing fraud or crime.  
**All Personal Information:** We will use all the Personal Information we collect to monitor and improve our site, our app, our procedures and processes. We also use the Personal Information we collect to help us develop new products and services.

At various places on our site or our app you may be requested to enter certain Personal Information. Personal Information that must be provided in order to use the requested services will be indicated at the time of collection. Other Personal Information that you are not required to provide in order to receive our services may be voluntarily given and you are free to decide not to give such Personal Information.

We may anonymize and aggregate any of the information we collect (so that it does not directly identify you). We may use anonymized information for purposes that include testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, improving our site and developing new products and features.

### INFORMATION WE SHARE WITH THIRD PARTIES

We may share your Personal Information with the following parties:

  1. **Companies in the same group of companies as us:** our subsidiaries (i.e. any organization we own or control) or our holding company or ultimate holding company (i.e. any organization that owns or controls us) and any subsidiaries they own. These companies will only use your Personal Information in the same way as we can under this privacy policy.
  2. **Service providers and advisors:** third parties who provide a service to us. For example, third-party service providers provide us with IT infrastructure, distributors, conference organisers, vendors who help us with our marketing processes, and those who assist us with technical support and provide professional services such as legal and accountancy services. These third parties will only be allowed to use your Personal Information in accordance with our instructions and will be required to keep your information secure.
  3. **Purchasers of our business:** Personal Information may be disclosed or transferred to buyers or perspective buyers of our business or any of our assets as part of any such sale.
  4. **Law enforcement, regulators and other parties for legal reasons:** third parties who we are under a legal obligation to disclose your Personal Information to or to whom we need to disclose your Personal Information to protect our rights, property or safety or to protect the rights, property or safety of others. We may also disclose Personal Information to third parties to help detect and investigate illegal activities and breaches of any agreement we have with you.

We do not disclose information about identifiable individuals to anyone else except as set out above. We may provide third parties with aggregate statistical information and analytics about users of our site or our app but we will make sure no one can be identified from this information before we disclose it.

### MARKETING AND ADVERTISING

From time to time we may contact you with information about our products and services. Most marketing messages we send will be by email but occasionally we may also contact you by SMS, mail or phone. If you are using our app we may also send you push notifications. If you do not want to receive marketing messages from us, you are always able to do so by directly contacting us as below in Section 4.4, or by using the unsubscribe function.

You can also change you marketing preference at a later date by following the instructions outlined below.   
**Email** – click on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of our marketing emails. If you have an online account with us you may also be able to opt-out of marketing emails through your account settings.   
**SMS** – please follow the stop SMS instructions in the marketing message you receive from us. If you have an online account with us you may also be able to opt-out of marketing SMS through your account settings.   
**App push notifications** – you can change your push notification preferences at anytime in the account settings for the app.   
If you receive marketing from us through other channels e.g. mail or by phone, and you no longer want to receive such messages, you can tell us to stop marketing to you by mail or phone marketing messages by using our contact details at the end of this privacy policy. Please note that most marketing messages we send will be by email.

Where you have given us permission to do so, we may share your contact details with selected third parties so that they can provide you with information about products and services that they believe may be of interest to you.

You can then let us know at any time that you no longer wish to receive marketing communications by sending an email to us at [marketing@cellsignal.com](mailto:marketing@cellsignal.com).

### ONLINE ADVERTISING

We, or our advertising partners, may show advertisements to you on our site, our app or on other websites or apps. To do this we, or our advertising partners, may collect information about you, about how you use or connect to our site, our app or the types of other web pages, social media services, content and ads you, or others who are using the device you connect to our site or app with, interact with, visit or view. The information collected might also include the IP address of the device you connect to our site or our app.

We, or our advertising partners, use the information that is collected to make sure the ads you see either on our site, our app, other parties’ websites and apps (where our partners have advertising space) are more relevant to you.

Sometimes we use cookies and similar technologies to provide this type of advertising. You can find out more about cookies and how to manage their use by reading our cookie policy.

### STORING AND TRANSFERRING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

**Cookies and Local Storage:** we may store information (which may include Personal Information) locally on your device using cookies and other browser and application storage methods. For further information please see our cookie policy.

**Security:** we implement appropriate technical and organizational measures to protect your Personal Information against accidental or unlawful destruction, loss, change, or damage.   
**International Transfers:** as stated above in Section 1.3, your Personal Information is likely to be transferred to other jurisdictions for processing and storage. Please review Section 1.3 for further details.

### OUR POLICY TOWARDS CHILDREN

Our site and our app are not directed to persons under 13 and we do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 13. If you become aware that your child has provided us with Personal Information, without your consent, then please contact us using the details below so that we can take steps to remove such information and terminate any account your child has created with us.

### ACCESSING AND CORRECTING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

If you are resident in certain countries, you might have certain rights in relation to your Personal Information: (i) the right to be informed about how your Personal Information is being used; (ii) the right to access the Personal Information we hold about you; and (iii) the right to request the correction of inaccurate personal data we hold about you and to request the blocking or deletion of your Personal Information where the processing does not comply with local data protection laws. To exercise any of the above rights, or if you have any questions relating to your rights, please contact us by using the details set out in the "Contacting Us" section below. Please provide as much information as you can about the Personal Information you are looking for and we will be happy to try and help you find it.

### LINKS TO THIRD PARTY SITES

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from third-party websites of our partner networks, advertisers, partner merchants, news publications, distributors and affiliates. If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for their policies. Please check the individual policies before you submit any information to those websites.

### INCORPORATION OF SERVICES AND CONTENTS FROM THIRD PARTIES INTO OUR WEBSITES

Content of third parties, such as videos from YouTube, RSS feeds or graphics from other websites, are or will be integrated into our site. This may require that the providers of the content ("third-party provider") will process the IP address or other Personal Information about you. Without this information the third-party provider may not be able to provide content for you to view or use. Where an IP address or other Personal Information is necessary for showing the third-party provider’s content, we try to use content only from those providers that use the IP address or other Personal Information only for the delivery of such content. However, we have no influence on whether or not the third-party provider will save the IP address or other Personal Information for their own use, e.g. for statistical purposes.

### CHANGES TO THIS POLICY

We may update this privacy policy from time to time and so you should review this policy periodically. When we change this privacy policy in a material way, we will update the "last modified" date at the bottom of this privacy policy. Changes to this privacy policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

### NOTICE TO YOU

If we need to provide you with information about something, whether for legal, marketing or other business-related purposes, we will select what we believe is the best way to get in contact with you. We will usually do this through email or by placing a notice on our site. The fact that we may send notices to you will not stop you from being able to opt out of certain types of contact as described in this privacy policy.

### CONTACTING US

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcome and should be addressed to:

[Cell Signaling Technology, Inc.   
3 Trask Lane, Danvers, Massachusetts 01923, U.S.   
privacy@cellsignal.com](mailto:privacy@cellsignal.com)

This Privacy Policy was last modified on 31 August 2016.
